# **Aaron Niskin**

3415 Chase Ave – Miami Beach, FL 33140

☎ (305) 894-6475 • ☑ aaron@niskin.org • ≅ aaron.niskin.org
https://www.linkedin.com/in/aaron-niskin

HR Department October 8, 2016

BlackRock 40 East 52nd Street 10022 New York, NY

Dear Sir or Madam,

When my professor, Dr. Gary Kalmanovich, first told me about Jacopo Dalmasso's research with BlackRock, my interest in BlackRock solidified. Some people find satisfaction in learning a thing and sticking with it. I am not one of those people. I prefer to live on the edge of my own understanding, constantly venturing further into the unknown. This outlook has resulted in my taking nearly every Math course FIU had to offer, and my interest in entering the field of Finance. This preference is not solely for personal growth; it has also led to many workplace improvements.

As an example, I recall one instance from my Army days. For several missions, we would perform our standard pre-mission communications checks without any issues, but later on we would find ourselves unable to communicate. Our Commo Sergeant said these were unavoidable phenomena, which didn't sound reasonable to me. I (a Private at the time) conducted my own investigation. It turns out that these radios have to be synced in order to communicate (a cryptographic necessity), and when portions of the unit were separated by land barriers for a few minutes they would fall out of sync. I discovered that this, being a known problem, has a solution and I re-engineered our company radios and we never had that problem again.

I believe my penchant for learning, problem solving, and optimization would make me a valuable member of the BlackRock team. I expect the work to be challenging, but I am motivated by challenges. I am looking forward to late nights with textbooks and my computer, finding ways to optimize code, etc.

Thank you very much for your time and consideration. If you have any questions and or comments, please feel free to contact me at any time.

Sincerely yours,

Aaron Niskin

Attached: Resumé

# **Aaron Niskin**

3415 Chase Ave - Miami Beach, FL 33140

**☎** (305) 894-6475 • ⊠ aaron@niskin.org • ☐ aaron.niskin.org https://www.linkedin.com/in/aaron-niskin

# Skills and Languages

Advanced: Spanish | JAVASCRIPT, HTML, PYTHON, R

Intermediate: Hebrew | CLOJURE, SCHEME, HOPLON, CSS, MYSQL, POSTGRESQL, NODEJS

Basic: German | JAVA, HASKELL, MONGODB, LATEX, MATLAB, OCTAVE

### **Education**

New College of Florida

Master's In Data Science

2016–(2018)

### Florida International University

Miami
Physics and English 2012–2015

- Graduated Cum Laude GPA - 3.64 (3.79 in major)

- Dean's List (6 times)

## **Selected Courses**

Algebraic GeometryDifferential Geometry

Abstract Algebra (2 semesters)Point Set Topology

Classical Mechanics (2 semesters)
 Homology of Simplicial Complexes

- Thermodynamics - Advanced Calculus in  $\mathbb{R}^n$  (2 semesters)

# **Experience**

STEM.....

#### Florida Vocation Institute

Miami

Computer Science Instructor

2015–2016

- Taught and created syllabi for courses in HTML, CSS, CSS-Frameworks, JavaScript, SQL, MongoDB, NodeJS, Functional-Programming, and Basic-Logic
- Created a free online course intended to teach aspiring students about the above subjects through interesting projects (currently live at www.fvi-grad.com)

### Math-Busters (www.Math-Busters.com)

Miami

Co-founder and Math/Science/Computing Tutor

2010-2015

- Tutored all levels of students from Elementary School to upper-level University students
- Maintained a perfect five-star rating on Wyzant.com (with over 100 ratings and over 450 hours logged)

# 1-38 Infantry Regiment, 4/2 ID, US Army

Fort Lewis, WA

Infantryman

2006-2009

- Deployed to Iraq for OIF V from 2007-2008
- Held Team Leader, Rifleman, M-240B Machine Gunner, M-249 SAW gunner, RTO, Grenadier, and Marksman positions
- Combat Lifesaver certification
- Fought forest fires in Winthrop, Washington.

#### 478th Civilian Affairs Battalion, US Army

Perrine, FL 2004-2006

Civil Affairs Specialist

- Trained at the John F. Kennedy Special Warfare Center and School in Fort Bragg, NC for 6 months.
- Obtained Secret Clearance